# WAYNE TIPTON

## CONTACT

**EMAIL:** wayne.tipton@gmail.com

**PHONE**: 469-274-0250

## **PORTFOLIO WEBSITE:**

https://www.waynetipton.com

#### LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/waynetipton/

#### **PROFILE**

I'm driven by turning ideas into reality. Web development has never been "just a job" for me. What started as a simple "Hello World" program has become a full-fledged passion that gets more exciting with each new experience.

I'm a web developer because I love the unique blend of problem-solving, technology, creativity, and communication that's essential to producing something meaningful.

## **QUALIFICATIONS**

- Demonstrated basic proficiency in coding in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SASS
- Demonstrated basic knowledge of a front-end JS framework React.
- Proficiency in code management git version control
- Proficient in creating cross-browser and cross-platform compatible content
- Proficient understanding of responsive coding and design
- Proficient with web testing methodologies and tools
- Good knowledge of creative and current web analytics and reporting tools
- A helpful "can-do" attitude
- Enjoys working on multiple projects, innovating on the go, and ready for a challenge

## WFB DFVFI OPFR

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Freelance Frontend Web Developer at Accurate Digital Marketing

Feb 2017 – Present

☆ Re-designed WordPress website improving Google mobile speed score from 56 to 95.

☆ Developed React single page landing pages for Google Ads campaigns generating 8% CTR.

 $\Delta$  Developed conceptual designs for clients winning over \$8,258 of monthly business.

## 2<sup>nd</sup> Vice President Systems Administrator at Northern Trust

Oct 2006 - Feb 2018

☆ Regional project manager delivered \$15MM virtual computing platform on time and under budget.

☆ VMWare vCenter & vSphere virtual machine administration with 98% "first touch" resolution score.

☆ 8.67% network performance improvement as project lead on WAN Installation initiative.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Boston University**

MS Data Analytics 2015 - 2017 **University of Phoenix** 

BS Information Technology 2002 - 2004

## **MILITARY**

## **United States Navy**

Petty Officer 2<sup>nd</sup> Class Electronics Technician

## **SKILLS**

### **Technology**

React JS, Native
Redux
JavaScript ES 6
HTML 5
CSS 3
Bootstrap
Photo and video editing

### **Core Competencies**

Leadership and communication Technology problem solving Public Speaking Analytical/quantitative skills Written communication Strong interpersonal skills